Finding Aid for the Philip Marshall Connelly Collection of Los Angeles CIO Industrial Union Council Records, 1942-1957 LSC.2015
UCLA Library Special Collections
Philip Marshall Connelly Collection of Los Angeles CIO Industrial Union Council records
1942-1957
UCLA Library Special Collections
Connelly, Philip Marshall
LSC.2015
2.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
2.5 Linear Feet (2 oversize boxes)
5 boxes (2.5 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ted Ellsworth, 1970.
Purchase, 1972.
Collection was originally housed in the UCLA Institute of Industrial Relations Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: UCLA Catalog Record ID: 999645103606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, ephemera, and photographs relating to the Los Angeles labor movement and activities during the 1940s and 1950s. Includes files on 1948 national CIO convention, Henry Wallace third party movement, Mexican and South American labor, U.S. motors strike, opposition to 1946 subversives act, Catholic Interracial Council, anti-Taft-Hartley campaign, relations with Los Angeles mayor Fletcher Bowron, black community relations, and AFL-CIO Brotherhood cooperation.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Los Angeles CIO (Boxes 1-3).
Ford-CIO, ca. 1948-50 (Boxes 4-5).
Scrapbook clippings, poster layouts, photographs (Box 6).
Poster of Vicente Lombardo Toledano (Box 7).
Labor unions -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.); Connelly, Philip Marshall--Archives.
- Los Angeles CIO
  - Council annual elections. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charges against N.Y. council. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National CIO effort to organize BRT members in Southern California. Also printing craftsmen into lithographers., (1946) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Early shoe worker organization dispute with AFL (William Green signature). (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Report to Los Angeles council re national CIO convention at Portland., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Challenged election of council delegate to national convention., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Political split over Marshall Plan and Third party threat. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Attack on council sponsored personnel on community agencies by right wing. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - council election., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Steelworkers drive against Wallace - Third party proponents. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Take over activities - pro and con. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History campaign to oust Bridges as California director. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - First Herald-Express strike, (1946). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Huntington Park Bulletin - strike. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - CIO council vs. publications re Third party candidates. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - CIO council relations with Mexican and South American labor. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Early CIO in California. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - CIO building photographs. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Early Hearst guild organizing in Los Angeles and elsewhere. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Motors strike. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Labor community campaign vs. G.L.K. Smith. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Opposition to subversives act., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - CIO council campaigns for Palestine defense. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CIO and Catholic Interracial Council. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Council civil rights fights vs. police brutality. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Labor day parades. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Labor day parade photos, also other years. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Guild left-right issues in., 1950s (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Anti Taft-Harley campaign. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - North American Aircraft pre-war strike-labor wartime follow-ups. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hollywood Citizen News strike. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hollywood Citizen News strike photos. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - campaign vs. Smith - Connelly congressmen., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Relations with Mayor Bowron (up and down). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Council - Negro community relations. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Anti Munt-Nixon Bill campaign photos. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - UE national convention in Long Beach. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Council war cooperation activities. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Visit to Los Angeles by various CIO and other "brass." (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photo instances of AFL-CIO Brotherhood cooperation. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Los Angeles CIO Council Report. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Memorabilia. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Scrapbook re industrial labor clippings,., July 1945-February 1946 (Box 6)
- Poster layouts., [8 items]. (Box 6)
- Photographs re union activities,., ca. 1942-1945; [15 photos]. (Box 6)
- Files re Ford-CIO,., ca. 1948-1950 (Box 6)
- Chronological Files
  - Correspondence. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ., January-February 1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ., March 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ., April-May 1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ., June-August 1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ., January-April 1949 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ., May-December 1949 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous materials, unsorted. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, unsorted. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Subject Files
  - File of New York Guild paper, Front Page,., January 1947-September 1948 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reisel material and CIO News times of council take-over. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Council ouster campaign throughout the country other than California. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Literature re split over Marshall Plan and Wallace "third party" move. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous printed material. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Poster of Vicente Lombardo Toledano. (Box 7)
  General note
  (Formerly in Box 1, folder 16.)